Ian De Bie

18102 San Gabriel Ave, Cerritos, CA 90703

Phone: 714.273.8994 • Email: ian@debie.us • Profiles: in



Software Engineer

OBJECTIVE

Mine is a unique situation. After many years in a stable career as an Accounting Manager, discovered my true passion is in programming. Took a chance and went back to school, and I have graduated with my BS in Computer Science. Looking for an opportunity as a Software Engineer. Dedicated worker, proven quick learner, and problem solver who is eager to contribute to the company's overall growth.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, December 2019

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, Utah

Excellence Award - For exemplary work in the Introduction to Artificial Intelligence

COURSEWORK

- Calculus I
- Software Engineering
- Computer Architecture
- Software Quality Assurance
- Structured Query Language
- Discrete Mathematics I & II
- Web Development Foundation

- Scripting and Programming Found. & Appl.
- Data Management Foundation & Application
- Software I & II Advanced Java Concepts
- Introduction to Artificial Intelligence
- Data Structures and Algorithms, I & II
- Network and Security Foundation
- Operating Systems for Programmers

SKILLS



Python

Javascript

C++

PHP

SQL

HTML

SCSS

PROJECTS

My website ian.debie.us has screenshots available for each of the projects listed below. In addition, there are many more projects located in my Github repositories.

Appointment schedule app - built with Java | JavaFX | MySQL | SceneBuilder

Belle Moda dashboard built with PHP | Javascript | Laravel | Heroku Postgres

Prediction model built with Python | Javascript | Django | Heroku Postgres

Finance dashboard built with Python | Javascript | Flask | IEX API | SQLite3

Ravenous search built with React.js | Node.js | Yelp API

Visual programming sandbox built with Scratch @Scratch.MIT.edu

Cryptocurrency price retrieval built with Python | SQLite3 | CoinAPI.io API

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate 1Z0-071, (10/28/2019) CompTIA Project+, (5/2/2019) CIW Site Development Associate, (2/4/2019) Axelos ITIL Foundation Cert, (10/18/2019)

EXPERIENCE

Ingram Micro, Inc • Irvine, CA (November 2011 – April 2019)

Accounting Manager (July 2015 – April 2019)

- Promoted by demonstrating core competencies and vast knowledge of company operations impacting our department
- Managed over \$3 billion in receivables per year for special pricing programs
- Used Python to create automation scripts to retrieve online reports
- Received recognition for creating various Excel templates using VBA
- Responsible for solving daily escalations from internal and external customers
- Worked extensively with SQL developers designing in-house application

Senior Accountant (August 2013 – June 2015)

Promoted after being recognized for personally maintaining \$0 aging over 90 days on over \$500 million in special pricing program receivables annually
Accountant II (November 2011 – July 2013)

- Established and cultivated relationships with our vendors driving timely resolution of outstanding receivables
- Utilized VBA and SQL to improve process efficiencies

Insight • Tempe, AZ (January 2009 – October 2011)

Senior Analyst (April 2010 – October 2011)

- Promoted for managing the largest vendor program with lowest open aging Analyst (January 2009 March 2010)
 - Exceeded expectations for goals each year for write-off and aging metrics

Cashcall • Anaheim, CA (2005 - 2008)

Production Manager (2007 - 2008)

• Promoted due to ability to motivate the team and assist customers, and had a high level of knowledge of the loan product programs

Loan Agent (2005 – 2007)

• Won multiple sales contests receiving over \$50K in bonus commissions

Potter Roemer • Santa Ana, CA (1999 - 2005)

Accounting Manager (2003 - 2005)

- Promoted based on exemplary performance of prior duties
- Managed AP, AR, and payroll teams, Cost and Staff Accountants

Cost Accountant (2002 - 2003)

- Promoted after demonstrating competencies in analysis and Excel
- Responsible for creating product bill of materials and physical inventory
- Prepared budget and forecast reporting in Excel

Staff Accountant (1999 - 2001)

- Prepared financial statements, sales/use tax returns, bank reconciliations
- Received recognition for reconciling over 12 months of unreconciled accounts

Fisher Service Company • Paramount, CA (1996 - 1999)

Payroll Administrator (1998 - 1999)

- Promoted due to mastery of AP position by being efficient and accurate Accounts Payable (1996 1998)
 - Issue payments for approved purchase orders and review AP GL entries

Enterprise Rent-A-Car • Carson, CA (1993 - 1996)

Leasing Accountant (1995 - 1996)

- Promoted based on attention to detail in GL by catching erroneous entries Accountant I (1993 1995)
 - General Ledger analysis and reporting

UPS United Parcel Service • Cerritos, CA (1992 - 1993)

Pre-loader Package Handler (1992 - 1993)

Won multiple employee awards for speed and accuracy of loading trucks